{
    "id": "5d3a3133a1264f08af53ddbc33f1818d",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I would have ..................... a gypsy.",
            "description": "To take somebody for a gypsy is to think that they are a gypsy.",
            "answers": [
                "brought him for",
                "taken him for",
                "taken him in"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you mind if I ………………. here until the rain stops?",
            "description": "After do you mind, present tenses are used.",
            "answers": [
                "stay",
                "stayed",
                "will stay"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind if I …………….. some music?",
            "description": "After would you mind, we use a simple past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "play",
                "played",
                "had played"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Grandmother …………………. go to hospital yesterday.",
            "description": "Must and should have present or future meanings. To talk about necessity in the past, we use ‘had to’.",
            "answers": [
                "have to",
                "must",
                "should",
                "had to"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………….. home earlier, I wouldn’t have missed the train.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have left",
                "left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If he had driven carelessly, he ………………… an accident.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "would have",
                "would have had"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He is ……………… to live in a finer house.",
            "description": "When enough is used as an adverb, it goes after the adjective it modifies.",
            "answers": [
                "enough rich",
                "rich enough",
                "too rich"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He used a hammer …………….. drive a nail into the wall.",
            "description": "\"In order to\" is more emphatic than the infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "in order to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I was so bewildered …………….. I could not say a word.",
            "description": "Note the pattern so…that. The above sentence can also be written as: ‘I was too bewildered to say a word’.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "as to",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………….. the last day of our holiday, it rained.",
            "description": "We use on with days.",
            "answers": [
                "On",
                "In",
                "At"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The house is burning. It is ……………… fire.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "under",
                "on",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Will you lend me the scissors when you are finished ………… them?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "by",
                "with",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}